# **Kush Patel**

# Web/Full-Stack Developer

Phone: 647-830-4509 | Email: <a href="mailto:kushrpatel06@yahoo.com">kushrpatel06@yahoo.com</a> | Brampton, ON | LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:kushrpatel06/">kushrpatel06/</a> | GitHub: <a href="mailto:family60">family60</a> | Portfolio: <a href="mailto:kush-patel">kushrpatel06/</a> | GitHub: <a href="mailto:family60">family60</a> | Portfolio: <a href="mailto:kush-patel">family60</a> | Portfolio: <a href="mailto:kush-patel">fa

# **SUMMARY**

Web/Full-Stack developer with over two years of experience in building projects from ideation to execution. Proven ability to take project ideas from early stages of wire-framing and development all the way through to deployment and maintenance in a fast-paced environment. Earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Toronto. Quick learner who adapts to the task at hand with punctuality, quality design, and scalability in mind.

### **SKILLS AND TOOLS**

JavaScript(es6), HTML5, CSS, Node.js/Express, React.js, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, MongoDB (Mongoose), MySQL (Sequelize), GraphQL, API's, JSON, CL, AWS, Responsive Web Design, MERN stack, MVC, handlebars, Json Web Tokens (JWT), Content Management Systems (CMS), Jest, DOM, Debugging

Git, VS Code, Postman, Chrome Developer Tools, NPM, Word, Excel

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Baby Phoenix Studios - Web Developer

2023-Present

Worked with the developers at Baby Phoenix Studios to create a professional looking landing page for their studio website.

- Coordinated a plan to fulfill project MVP's and meet deadlines accordingly.
- Managed and organized GitHub repo to increase organization and code readability.
- Fixed bugs on a daily basis and handled over 5 feature request tickets every week.
- Decreased page load times by 21% and collaborated in reducing redundant CSS to increase PWA score by over 7%.

# Anime Bootcamp - Full Stack Developer

2022-2023

Co-developed a user-friendly, intuitive and secure website from scratch with interactive features to optimize traffic and user experience using the MERN stack.

- Troubleshooted problems regarding login and signup using JWT.
- Reduced number of calls to API's by half by solving a few problems with hooks in React.js
- Restructured MongoDB model and GraphQL queries to be more readable and increase overall organization if codebase.
- Helped modify CSS to be mobile responsive and improved progressive web application score by 18%

# Hospital DB – Full Stack Developer

2022-2022

Developed with a small group of individuals to help create more user-friendly version of the CMS styled applications that some hospitals have been using for a long period of time.

- Worked on Authentication using JSON Web Tokens (JWT).
- Created the express handlebar template for patients table page and its corresponding CRUD operations.
- Solved major bugs and design flaws that held the team back from meeting deadlines (average of 1 week late)
- Pushed the motion to use Express Handlebars to increase organization of codebase and as an alternative to previous method of handling the front-end.

### **PROJECTS**

### Google Book Search Engine | /google-books-search | /github/books

- Used JWT to allow users to login and sign up.
- Implemented features that allowed users to search for books, remove books from their collection, see more details on each book, etc.
- This was done using GraphQL to fetch data from Google Books API, Mongoose to save user info and saved books.
- Express and Apollo server was used in tangent with React to help handle the backend and render components to the front end.

# Online Text Editor | <u>/online-note-taker</u> | <u>/github/Note</u>

- Application that allows user to write and save notes they make.
- Saving notes in the application so the next time the user opens the application, their notes load up by default.
- Used Express.js to save and read the note data from a JSON file.

### Team Profile Generator | /github/Team-Profile-Generator

- Application that creates a team of employees and renders it to an html page.
- Used Jest for testing purposes.
- Used Inquirer to prompt user's questions that filled up the html page with their team's profile data.
- After finishing with all questions in the command line, users can use/open the html page generated based on their answers.

### README.md Generator | /github/ReadMe-Generator

- An application using node.js and Inquirer library that prompts developers to create professional looking README.md files for their personal or even professional projects.
- After filling in the questions, the resulting data writes into a README.md file in the Develop/ directory of this project folder.
- This file correctly registers as a valid README.md file for any given GitHub repository.

### Weather Dashboard | <u>/Weather-Dashboard</u> | <u>/github/Weather</u>

- The program allows users to enter a city name and search for the current forecast and also the next five days for that city.
- Stored unique city names in the users local storage and rendered as input fields that the user can click on to search via their search history.
- The page background changes dynamically based on the city the user searched for.
- Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, and two third party API's: "Open Weather Api" for the weather data and "Unsplashed" for the background images.

### **EDUCATION**

### Certificate in Full Stack Development

SCS • University of Toronto • 27 King's College Cir, Toronto, ON M5S • 3.9

### **Diploma of Computer Programming**

University of Guelph-Humber • 207 Humber College Blvd, Etobicoke, ON M9W 5L7 • 3.7

#### **COURSEWORK**

#### Crash course in AWS - University of Toronto

I Learned how to apply my current understanding of programming and apply to create backend code to run on a AWS based application

### JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures - freecodecamp.org

I learned to tackle logic-based problems in JavaScript and solve them using skills I learned through the course exercises.